In this video, we will talk about the policies of two health
insurance companies. The
first one is Star Health's Young Star
policies. The second one is Nivea Gufa and Max's
plan. Both the products are
excellent products of both the companies. They are unique
products and hot selling products. We will
compare apple to apple, we
will compare point to point, on this point which
policy is good, on which point which
policy is lacking and accordingly we will
suggest for ourselves, we will analyze for ourselves
which policy is best for us
and in which way, keeping which benefit in mind, it will be best
for us. Let's
discuss.
[Music] The
first one is Star Health's Young Star. The second one is the
plan of both. The names of the plans have become clear.
[Music] It is
increasing so much, so
according to our value and the
kind of
atmosphere we are living in, we will have to
think accordingly and now we will have to take a plan accordingly.
This plan has been kept for Rs 50 lakh 2 crore and I am explaining to you
that the room rent facility
cannot go above this, you
cannot go above a single room, you
can take a room whether yours  If you are a man then
you can go for deluxe also
[music]
yes then they go for ICU limit in both of them there is
no difference in it,
basically if I tell you the meaning of pre hospital is that
if you are getting admitted and
whatever expenses you have incurred before getting admitted
due to that disease then for how many days
maximum it is covered in back then it is
60 days in both the dates is equal then we go for
post hospital there is
90 days coverage in hospital it means
when you come out of the hospital
after that you have to take a lot of medicines
you have to go through a lot of check ups a lot of
tests so for how many days does it
keep you covered even after getting out so star
young star
is a big differentiating point
so this is not happening in the hospital for more than 2000
so for emergency suppose
you have to go to Mumbai or
you have to go out of the country then there should be
air ambulance facilities
and there you see
in the lines of Nivya now you get 2.5 lakh
cashless and investment  You will get it
in one go, you cannot charge more than this,
now go for De Care, De Care
facility is available in both,
suppose in any situation
your operation is done within three-four hours
and you are discharged,
some diseases are such that they do
not stop the operation in a very short time, they do
not stop it for one day, two, two-three days, if there is
any therapy done by laser or something like that
and they will send you away within three-four hours, then it is
called Dagar, it
is available in both, now let's go, this is a very
unique feature of
Bisleri treatment, what has happened today,
what happened during the time of Corona, that people are
not going to the hospital, they should get it checked by a doctor
and after that they are not getting a seat, bedsheet or a
bed in the hospital,
so what is in that case, if the doctor
writes on their prescription that
their entire treatment has to be done at home, then will it be
covered in it or not, so you
take it here, in Young Star it
is not covered in your policy, suppose
your entire treatment has to be done at home  The
nurse doctor will come to your home and give you
treatment, that is not covered
in this. Annual health checkup,
now see, if
I have taken a family policy in Star, then it will
not cost more than Rs. 5000. If I have
four people in my family floor, then I will have to spend Rs.
5000 on it. The
tests of all four people will have to be done for Rs. 5000. If
I have taken an individual policy, then they will
not give me more than Rs. 3.5 thousand.
Okay, you can go and get a medical checkup done for one person in a year for Rs. 3-30 thousand.
You can get an
annual health checkup done
from you. In case of Nirvijay,
if you have a
family policy, then you will be given coverage up to Rs. 10,000.
If you have an individual policy, then
you will be given coverage of Rs. 5000. Okay, so
if it is a family floater, if there are three or
four people in that policy, then
you are getting all the tests done for all four people for Rs. 10,000 only.
Okay, now this goes to organ donor, if
some part of someone's body is damaged,
liver is damaged or  If
someone donates to someone else, then the
person who is donating will also have to bear the
expenses in the hospital.
Organ donors are not covered in this. In Star policies, the
expenses are 50 lakhs,
so you can take up to 50 lakhs.
If there is any delay for the donor, then the
company will bear the expenses till that time.
Now, there is a very unique feature
in this policy, you will get restoration in Star policies. I
mean, I have a
policy of 50 lakhs, if I get admitted and this
exhaustion will end,
I am getting admitted again in the same financial year
and I need it, then I will get one more
refilling, I will get ₹50 lakhs again.
Okay, now if I need it again for the third time in the same financial
year, then it will
not be available, but in Nivya policies,
restoration is unlimited.
If my policy expires in August,
next year in 2023,
I can take 50-50 lakhs 10 times in between this term,
take coverage 20 times.  I can
take it 30 times as long as
I need it.
I and my family members may have different
diseases. It can be for any disease as well. There is no
problem. If today I am having
stomach ache and I get admitted and it costs
me Rs 50 lakhs, then
next time I am getting admitted again for stomach ache
and the
cost is again Rs 50 lakhs, which is less than that. I
can get it after getting admitted
and this unlimited time is for my stomach today. If
something happens to me tomorrow or to someone else or to any of my family members, then
we can take this unlimited time. There is a
unique feature that totally makes it different. I
mean, if we make this plan
different from all other plans,
now let's go to the NCB. The
NCB in the Star plan is increasing by 20% and now it will
go to 200%, which means your policy will double in 5 years.
Okay, Star plan, but here you can go to the
Rex plan next year.  Meaning if your policy is of 50
lakhs then if it increases by 50% then it will become
around 75 lakhs,
next year it will be of one crore, meaning
your policy will double in 2 years but
in Star policy it will double in 5 years and the
condition for this MCB increase is that
if you do not take the claim in the
year in which it has to increase your answer also. If
a person is admitted then he is
not doing a job at the time of admission, his salary means he is
not doing a job as per the insurance,
he is not doing a job as per his family also,
so now suppose he is in the hospital for 10 days, then
in Young Star policy
you will get Rs. 1000 for this policy
and if you are admitted once in the hospital for
30 days there is a
big difference and if he is admitted for 10 days, he will get Rs.
7000 here, he cannot get more than this and
here in the same 10 days he got
Rs. 40 * 10, i.e. 40000, it was found that
his premium was also the same  There is
more than that, you have got it here, this is the thing that
makes it unique, there are some such
terms and features on New Abbu which really make it
worthwhile, the consumer policy
of consumer coverage
means what is there in today's date
that some companies will
take some charges from you but the
amount of consumables which the hospital people give you, they will
not allow it to be charged but
what is there here, you will have to pay for the consumables,
that is, in Star there are plastic items,
syringes and some such items for which
you will have to pay for them in Young Star
but what is there here is Shivgarh additional
feature in which a maximum amount of Rs. 1500 is spent,
because of that, whatever consumable
items are added on at the time of your claim,
you will not have to pay for them,
you will have to pay zero amount, this is a very unique
feature and every policy should be
taken, there are
no internal restrictions, in this the individual should be
18 years old and
maximum can take up to 65 and there is no
restriction on Nivya people
but in Star's Young Star policy
You cannot avail this plan after 40 years.
Even in India, there is no area wise payment
that means you will have to pay more money here
or you will not get the full claim in advance. There is nothing like that. Yes, as
I told you about the rent of a room, if you take a
single room, if you take a deluxe room,
which I told you about, or take something like that,
if the charges for that single room are
higher than that, that is, whatever
the amount is more, then
whatever your overall bill is being made or the
total bill of your claim is being made,
you will have to pay that amount extra from that as well in the same ratio.
Suppose, Star
Young Star allows me a room of only Rs. 10,000
and you have given me a room of Rs. 12,000 and you are
admitted for 10 days, then your
room rent will be Rs. 20,000,
20,000 extra as per 12,000. So,
if your total bill comes to Rs. 12 lakh, then
you will be given a claim of only Rs. 10 lakh and
that too with 20% reduction from that.  We will do it because
of room rent. This is a very big imagination
of the plan. According to me, whichever
plan you take, it should be of optimum level
and should be of supreme level. When you are paying the money, then there is a
little difference. There is not
much difference in the premium between the two.
But these features are such that
your mind remains very relaxed.
Having or not having maternity is the same.
In a delivery, whether it is normal or cesarean,
and that will be 36, that is, 3 years and you will get only up to Rs. 30,000.
In metro cities, they do not give
less than Rs. 2 lakh anywhere as of today. I will
tell you about the special features of both these products once. One of them is the
waiting period, that is Young Star's plus,
but the one in Nivea has many such points
which make it better than other insurance companies and Young Star.
Unique Restoration
Limited
Home Care Home Health Care, which gets
you treated at your home if the doctor
recommends you. So
after analyzing all the points and doing everything, it comes out that some
points are Star  These are also good, nothing
brother, you have to see which
point suits me the most, if I look at myself then I
understand that Nivea
is a great star, young star,
so I will go with Nivea and think about
yourself, whatever you like, you can take
all the Apple points and 2 points, I have given it to you after
comparing, thank you.